college english test band four part two listening comprehension
大学英语四级考试第二部分 听力理解
section a
A节
Directions in this section
说明：在本节中
You will hear three news reports
你将听到三篇新闻报道
At the end of each news report
每篇新闻报道结束后
You will hear two or three questions
你将听到两到三个问题
Both the news report and the questions will be spoken only once
新闻报道和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c and d
B、C和D
then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one
然后在答题卡一上
With a single line through the center
用横线划过相应字母
news report one
新闻报道一
six people had to move away from their home to another place
周六主街一栋建筑发生火灾后
After a fire broke out in a building on main street saturday
六人不得不从家中搬到另一个地方
Officials said
官员说
firefighters responded to the three story building shortly after one pm
消防员下午一点后不久响应了这栋三层建筑
For a reported structure fire
接到结构火灾报告
According to norwalk deputy fire chief adam marowitz
据诺沃克消防副主管亚当·马罗维茨称
Mark owitz said cruise encountered heavy smoke coming from the second floor when they arrived
马罗维茨说，消防员到达时遇到二楼冒出的浓烟
a team of about twenty five firefighters
约二十五名消防员
Then spent about twenty five minutes extinguishing the flames
然后花了大约二十五分钟扑灭火焰
Officials described the structure as a mixed use building that features
官员将该建筑描述为混合用途建筑
commercial businesses on the first floor
一楼是商业
And residential on the second and third floors
二楼和三楼是住宅
town records list four apartments in the building
城镇记录显示该建筑有四套公寓
Due to smoke and heat damage
由于烟雾和热损坏
the four apartments were declared uninhabitable
四套公寓被宣布为不宜居住
And the six residents had to move to another place
六名居民不得不搬到另一个地方
Officials said
官员说
No injuries were reported in connection with the fire
据报道火灾没有造成人员伤亡
The norwalk fire marshal is investigating the cause and origin of the fire
诺沃克消防局长正在调查火灾的原因和起源
Questions one and two are based on the news report you have just heard
问题一和问题二基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question one
问题一
Why did the six residents have to find another place to stay
为什么六名居民不得不另找住处
question two
问题二
what does the news reports say the north walk fire marshal is doing
新闻报道说诺沃克消防局长正在做什么
News report two
新闻报道二
a new study has cast doubt on historic research
一项新研究对历史研究提出质疑
Suggesting that the season or month of someone's birth
表明某人的出生季节或月份
Is associated with an increased risk of certain mental health conditions
与某些心理健康状况的风险增加有关
the study looks at symptoms of anxiety and depression
该研究调查了焦虑和抑郁症状
Among more than seventy thousand older adults in europe
在七万多名欧洲老年人中
A number of past studies have found a link between season of birth and mental health diagnoses
许多过去的研究发现出生季节与心理健康诊断之间存在联系
Researchers have suggested that such links could arise from various things
研究人员提出，这种联系可能源于各种因素
These include nutrient intake
这些包括营养摄入
Sun exposure
阳光照射
Climate and disease exposure varying across the course of the year
气候和疾病暴露在一年中变化
However , evidence has been mixed
然而，证据不一
More recent studies have suggested that factors
最近的研究表明
such as social class or economic background
社会阶层或经济背景等因素
Have more to do with these diagnoses than month of birth
比出生月份与这些诊断关系更大
Overall , the new study found no significant relationship between participants
总体而言，新研究发现参与者
Month of birth and symptoms of depression or anxiety
出生月份与抑郁或焦虑症状之间没有显著关系
There was some variability in some countries
在一些国家有一些变化
In poland , depressive symptoms fluctuated a little depending on birth month
在波兰，抑郁症状根据出生月份略有波动
In the czech republic
在捷克共和国
The same was true of anxiety symptoms
焦虑症状也是如此
But on the whole there was no systematic pattern
但总体上没有系统性模式
Questions three and four are based on the news report you have just heard
问题三和问题四基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question three
问题三
What have a number of past studies found about season of birth
许多过去的研究关于出生季节发现了什么
question four
问题四
What did the new study find about the relationship between participants
新研究关于参与者出生月份与抑郁症状
month of birth and symptoms of depression
之间的关系发现了什么
News report three
新闻报道三
Genetic researchers in china have made a clone of a star police dog
中国的基因研究人员克隆了一只明星警犬
The clone was born in a laboratory in beijing in december
克隆犬于十二月出生在北京的一个实验室
Tests show that the clone and her mother are almost identical genetically
测试显示克隆犬和她的母亲在基因上几乎相同
The mother dog helped solve multiple murders and many other crimes
母犬帮助破获了多起谋杀案和许多其他犯罪
The clone has already performed better than traditionally bred dogs on several tests
克隆犬已经在几项测试中表现优于传统繁殖的狗
If the clone continues to perform as well as expected
如果克隆犬继续按预期表现
It could mean a huge reduction in the training time for police dogs
这可能意味着警犬训练时间大大减少
Which usually takes about five years
通常需要大约五年
The ultimate goal of scientists is to produce clones of talented police dogs
科学家的最终目标是生产有天赋警犬的克隆
That can be trained in months instead of years
可以在几个月而不是几年内训练
However , this goal is not yet possible
然而，这个目标尚未实现
Due to the current costs of the technology
由于当前技术的成本
This is not the first time a clone has been made of a star police dog
这不是第一次克隆明星警犬
In south korea
在韩国
Six clones began working with the police in two thousand eight
六只克隆犬于2008年开始与警方合作
Questions five to seven are based on the news report you have just heard
问题五至问题七基于你刚才听到的新闻报道
Question five
问题五
What did the researchers tests show about the cloned dog
研究人员的测试关于克隆犬显示了什么
question six
问题六
what is the scientist's purpose in cloning police dogs
科学家克隆警犬的目的是什么
question seven
问题七
why does the news reports say the scientist's goal is not yet possible
为什么新闻报道说科学家的目标尚未实现
Section b directions , in this section you will hear two long conversations
B节 说明：在本节中你将听到两段长对话
At the end of each conversation
每段对话结束后
You will hear four questions
你将听到四个问题
Both the conversation and the questions will be spoken only once
对话和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c and d
B、C和D
Then mark the corresponding letter on answer
然后在答题卡上
Sheet one with a single line through the center
用横线划过相应字母
Conversation one
对话一
Tom , did you see the article online about the new tv series based on the book
汤姆，你看到网上关于基于《三体》这本书的新电视剧的文章了吗
The three body problem
一位同事提到了这本书
A colleague mentioned the book
但我一直忙着写论文
But i've been so busy writing my thesis
好几个月没能看书消遣了
That i haven't been able to read for pleasure in months
嗯，听起来如果你要读什么消遣的话
Well , sounds like if you're going to read anything for fun
就是这本书，它是一位中国科幻作家写的
This is the book it's written by a chinese science fiction writer
我不记得他的名字了
I can't remember his name
但他总共写了三本书
But he's written three books in all
《三体》是系列的第一本
And the three body problem is the first in the series
我不想说太多，破坏你的阅读体验
I don't want to say too much and spoil it for you
但它确实有一些惊人的技术和社会学概念
But it's definitely got some amazing technological and sociological concepts in it
听起来确实符合我的口味
It does sound like it would suit my taste
但如果他们现在正在制作电视剧
But if they are making a tv series based on it now
我不知道我应该先看书还是先看剧
I don't know if i should read the book or watch the show first
我觉得最好先看书
I think it's better to read the book first
电视剧或电影比书好的情况很少
it's rare for the show or movie to be better than the book
然后你只会毁了这本书
And then you just end up ruining the book for yourself
如果剧不好的话
If the show isn't very good
节目什么时候开始
When is the show supposed to start
我有点被数据量压倒了
I'm a bit overwhelmed with the amount of data
我还需要收集来完成论文
I still need to collect to finish my thesis
但我还是需要放松
But i still need to relax
我不记得确切时间，很快
Sometimes i can't remember exactly it's pretty soon
而且会很长
And it's going to be quite long
有二十四集
There are twenty four episodes
嗯，也许你可以下载电子版
Well , maybe you could download an electronic copy of the book
试着在节目开始前读完
And try to read it before the show starts
这是个好主意
that's a good idea
然后也许我们可以一起看剧
And then maybe we can watch the series together
谢谢你的建议！没问题
Thanks for the tip palace ! no problem
问题八至问题十一基于你刚才听到的对话
Questions eight to eleven are based on the conversation you have just heard
问题八
Question eight
男子是如何了解到《三体》这本书的
How did the man get to know about the book
《三体》
the three body problem
问题九
Question nine
女子说她不记得这本书作者的什么
What does the woman say she can't remember about the books author
问题十
Question ten
男子需要做什么来完成论文
What does the man have to do to finish his thesis
问题十一
question eleven
男子在对话后最可能先做什么
Conversation two
对话二
Hello
你好
Good afternoon
下午好
i have an inquiry to make it's about the vegetarian food festival
我想咨询一下关于素食节
You are holding on the nineteenth of august at the newcastle city hall
你们将于8月19日在纽卡斯尔市政厅举办
Yes of course
是的，当然
My name's philip
我叫菲利普
How can i help you
我能为您做什么
it says on your website that you are still looking for vendors
你们网站上说你们还在寻找供应商
And i grow organic vegetables on my farm
我在农场种植有机蔬菜
As well as doing my own home baking
也自己烘焙
Would i be able to sell both the vegetables and items baked from them at the festival
我能在节日上出售蔬菜和用它们烘焙的产品吗
That's exactly the type of thing we are looking for
这正是我们在寻找的
We are getting close to the deadline
我们快到截止日期了
However do you prefer to fill out an application on the web
不过，您更喜欢在网上填写申请
or to print it out and fill it in by hand
还是打印出来手写
And then post it back to us
然后寄回给我们
remember that you will have to have all your certificates to hand
请记住，填写表格时必须准备好所有证书
When you are filling out the forms
因为标准很高
as the standards are high
在活动前会仔细检查
And they will be carefully checked before
任何人都能够在活动上出售产品之前
Anyone will be able to sell their produce at the event
我可以在你们网站上填写
i should be fine with doing it on your website
我已经有所有证书，我们也经营一家小农场商店
And i already have all my certificates as we run a small farm shop too
但你能给我你的详细地址吗
But can you give me your details anyway
当然
Sure
好的
Please address it to the organic organization
请寄到有机组织
Vendor applications one hundred and twelve queens road , newcastle
供应商申请 纽卡斯尔皇后路112号
Northumbria the post code is n u twenty nine three lj
诺森伯兰 邮编NU29 3LJ
Remember that the closing date is next tuesday
请记住截止日期是下周二
The twenty eighth of june
6月28日
That's absolutely wonderful
太好了
Thank you so much for your help
非常感谢你的帮助
Goodbye
再见
Questions twelve to fifteen are based on the conversation you have just heard
问题十二至问题十五基于你刚才听到的对话
Question twelve
问题十二
Why does the woman call the man
女子为什么给男子打电话
question thirteen
问题十三
what is the man still looking for
男子还在寻找什么
Question fourteen what does the man say they are getting close to
问题十四 男子说他们快到什么了
question fifteen what does the man finally ask the woman to remember
问题十五 男子最后让女子记住什么
Section c directions
C节 说明
In this section you will hear three passages
在本节中你将听到三篇文章
At the end of each passage
每篇文章结束后
You will hear three or four questions
你将听到三到四个问题
Both the passage and the questions will be spoken only once
文章和问题都只读一遍
After you hear a question
听完问题后
You must choose the best answer from the four choices marked a
你必须从标有A的四个选项中选出最佳答案
B , c and d
B、C和D
then mark the corresponding letter on answer sheet one with a single line through the center
然后在答题卡一上用横线划过相应字母
Passage . one
文章一
Supporters call it wild camping
支持者称之为野营
Opponents call it illegal camping
反对者称之为非法露营
what both sides accept is that there has been a boom in the past few months
双方都接受的是，过去几个月出现了激增
With increasing numbers of visitors pitching their tents on any bit of land they fancy in the uk
越来越多的游客在英国任何他们喜欢的土地上搭帐篷
In part
部分
this reflects the fact that official camp sites have been wholly or partially closed
这反映了官方露营地全部或部分关闭的事实
Or are overflowing in a summer
或者在夏天爆满
When fewer people are going abroad
出国的人更少
It is also cheap at a time
这也是一个便宜的时期
When many are worried about what the economic future holds
许多人对经济未来感到担忧
But it may also be an expression of a desire for going outdoors
但这也可能是对户外活动的渴望的表达
A response to the months of lockdown
对数月封锁的回应
Most of the coverage of the boom in wild camping has been negative
大多数关于野营激增的报道都是负面的
Camping in public parks has now been banned for august
公共公园露营已被禁止至八月
And the early part of september
和九月初
Because campers dump litter
因为露营者乱扔垃圾
Human waste and even their tents on the grassland
人类排泄物甚至把帐篷留在草地上
Similar action has been taken even in scotland
即使在苏格兰也采取了类似行动
Where camping is usually permitted on most of its open land
那里通常允许在大部分开放土地上露营
Clearly there have to be rules
显然必须有规则
It would make sense that wild campus need to ask for permission to camp from landowners
野营者需要向土地所有者请求露营许可才有意义
Especially outside scotland
特别是在苏格兰以外
Where the law is far more restrictive
那里的法律更加严格
It would be common sense for people to use small tent
人们使用小帐篷是常识
And leave no trace of their visit
不留痕迹
They have been attracted by a patch of land that is close to wilderness
他们被一片接近荒野的土地吸引
And it is their responsibility to keep it that way
保持原样是他们的责任
Questions sixteen to eighteen are based on the passage you have just heard
问题十六至问题十八基于你刚才听到的文章
Question sixteen
问题十六
Why has wild camping become popular in the uk
为什么野营在英国变得流行
Question seventeen why is camping banned for part of the summer in public parks
问题十七 为什么公共公园夏季部分时间禁止露营
question eighteen what does the speaker suggest campers do
问题十八 说话者建议露营者做什么
Passage two
文章二
Imagine boating down the amazon river
想象一下沿着亚马逊河划船
Minding your own business
做你自己的事
Calmly keeping an eye out for alarmingly large snakes
冷静地留意令人惊恐的大蛇
And a curious pink dolphin appears to swim alongside
一只好奇的粉红海豚出现并游在旁边
While this may seem like a mythical creature
虽然这看起来像神话生物
Pink dolphins do exist in the amazon region
粉红海豚确实存在于亚马逊地区
The amazon river dolphin is a giant among its species
亚马逊河海豚是其物种中的巨兽
It can measure up to two meters long
它可以长达两米
And weigh around two hundred and four kilograms
重约204公斤
Size isn't the only thing that sets the amazon river dolphin apart
体型不是亚马逊河海豚的唯一特点
Thriving in south american rivers and temporary lakes caused by seasonal flooding
在南美河流和季节性洪水造成的临时湖泊中繁衍生息
This freshwater dolphin is sometimes shockingly pink
这种淡水海豚有时呈惊人的粉红色
Although born gray males of the species are easily identified
虽然出生时是灰色的，该物种的雄性很容易识别
As they enter adulthood by a decisive pink shade
因为它们进入成年时会呈现明显的粉红色调
Their unusual coloring is believed to be the
它们不寻常的颜色被认为是
Result of scar tissue from dolphin fights
海豚打斗留下的疤痕组织的结果
Whether play fighting or a serious bid for a mate
无论是嬉戏打斗还是为配偶的认真争夺
The deeper the pink
粉红色越深
The more attractive the males are believed to be
雄性被认为越有吸引力
And the older the male
雄性越老
The more pink he will have
粉红色越多
There's also a theory that this color helps the dolphins more readily blend in with their surroundings
还有一种理论认为，这种颜色帮助海豚更容易融入周围环境
During heavy rains
在大雨期间
Rivers along the amazon rainforest turn a pink shade
亚马逊雨林的河流变成粉红色调
And with their pink coloring
凭借它们的粉红色
Male dolphins are harder to detect
雄性海豚更难被发现
The amazon wetland system
亚马逊湿地系统
Fed by the amazon river
由亚马逊河滋养
Is a crucial place for pink dolphins to breed
是粉红海豚繁殖的关键场所
And since two thousand and eighteen has been granted internationally protected status
自2018年以来已被授予国际保护地位
Questions nineteen to twenty one are based on the passage you have just heard
问题十九至问题二十一基于你刚才听到的文章
Question nineteen
问题十九
What does the passage say about pink dolphins
文章关于粉红海豚说了什么
Question twenty what is the unusual coloring of pink dolphins
问题二十 粉红海豚不寻常的颜色
Believed to originate in
被认为起源于什么
question twenty one what has become of the amazon wetland system since twenty eighteen
问题二十一 自2018年以来亚马逊湿地系统发生了什么
Passage three
文章三
In a new meryl lynch age wave survey
在一项新的美林年龄波调查中
A full seventy percent of the early adults said they've received financial support from their parents in the past year
整整70%的早期成年人说他们在过去一年中从父母那里获得了经济支持
And fifty eight percent said they couldn't afford their current lifestyles without it
58%说没有这些支持他们无法负担目前的生活方式
The most common types of financial support include cell phone plans
最常见的经济支持类型包括手机计划
Food
食物
School costs and car expenses
学校费用和汽车费用
Parental financial support of early adults , said ken dickfild
年龄波首席执行官肯·迪克菲尔德说
Ceo of age wave is the new normal
父母对早期成年人的经济支持是新常态
but sixty four percent of the young adult surveyed said
但64%的受访年轻成年人说
parents financial support to children ed twenty five to thirty four is a bad thing
父母对25至34岁孩子的经济支持是坏事
Because it makes those kids dependent
因为这使这些孩子变得依赖
By contrast , only twenty nine percent
相比之下，只有29%
Thought supporting men and women aged eighteen to twenty four is bad
认为支持18至24岁的男性和女性是坏事
The remaining seventy one percent thought that assistance helps the adult children get ahead
其余71%认为这种帮助有助于成年子女取得进步
Dick fault believes the young women and men surveyed
迪克菲尔德认为受访的年轻男女
Were saying that by twenty five
在说25岁时
Young adults ought to be financially independent
年轻人应该经济独立
In fact , the respondents said financial independence defines adulthood
事实上，受访者说经济独立定义了成年
Financial independence is something they were struggling with and challenged by
经济独立是他们正在挣扎和面临挑战的东西
And it scared them a bit
这让他们有点害怕
Dick valt said
迪克菲尔德说
One big reason their struggling is attributed to college loans
他们挣扎的一个大原因是大学贷款
Of which the average amounts to thirty seven thousand dollars
平均金额为37000美元
Many of the parents have taken on college loans for the kids too
许多父母也为孩子承担了大学贷款
Sometimes at the expense of their own finances
有时以牺牲自己的财务为代价
In the survey , sixty percent of early adults defined financial success as being debt free
在调查中，60%的早期成年人将财务成功定义为无债务
Whether that's likely or even possible
这是否可能
anytime soon is anyone's guess
或者很快可能，谁也说不准
Questions twenty two to twenty five are based on the passage you have just heard
问题二十二至问题二十五基于你刚才听到的文章
Question twenty two
问题二十二
what do we learn from a new survey by marylynch age wave
我们从美林年龄波的新调查中了解到什么
Question twenty three
问题二十三
why did most young adults in the survey say
为什么调查中大多数年轻成年人说
Financial support to children aged twenty five to thirty four is a bad thing
对25至34岁孩子的经济支持是坏事
question twenty four what did the respondents and the survey say regarding financial independence
问题二十四 调查中受访者关于经济独立说了什么
Question twenty five
问题二十五
what is one big reason young adults are struggling
年轻成年人挣扎的一个大原因是什么
that's the end of listening comprehension
听力理解部分结束